https://www.electricaldiscountuk.co.uk/privacy-policy

Menu
TV Blu-ray & Home CinemaTV Blu-ray & Home CinemaA good entertainment system can act as the heart of the home, whether this is an LED Television or a complete Home Cinema set. Fortunately, at Electrical Discount UK, we have something for every budget, every size room and any amount of imagination.Televisions8KUp to 32inch TVs32inch to 39inch TVs40inch to 45inch TVs46inch to 55inch TVs56inch TVs and aboveOLED TVsQLED TVsPackagesBlu-ray and DVDBlu-Ray PlayersBlu-Ray RecordersUHD Blu-Ray PlayersDVD PlayersDVD RecordersBlu-ray DiscsHome CinemaHome Cinema SystemsSound BarsSet Top BoxesDigital Set Top BoxesSMART TV BoxesTV AccessoriesBracketsStands & CabinetsHDMI CablesOther TV AccessoriesRemote ControlsLaundry & DishwashersLaundry & DishwashersDoing the laundry and washing the dishes are tasks that no-one enjoys doing, but ones that have to be done.
Of course, both chores are made much easier thanks to the technology that is available to us today. Washing MachinesWashing MachinesIntegrated Washing MachinesWasher DryersWasher DryersIntegrated Washer DryersTumble DryersTumble DryersIntegrated Tumble DryersSpin DryersDishwashersDishwashersIntegrated DishwashersCompact DishwashersIroningIronsSteam Generator IronsLaundry AccessoriesLaundry & Dishwashers AccsCookers Hobs & HoodsCookers Hobs & HoodsCooking is obviously a necessity in the kitchen, and at Electrical Discount UK, we want to make it as fun and enjoyable as possible.
Choose from a range of high quality cookers, ovens and hobs to create the perfect kitchen environment for some undoubtedly splendid cooking.CookersElectric CookersGas CookersDual Fuel CookersCompact CookersOvensElectric OvensGas OvensOven & Hob PackagesRange CookersElectric Range CookersGas Range CookersDual Fuel Range CookersHobsElectric HobsGas HobsInduction HobsHoodsConventional HoodsChimney HoodsIsland HoodsIntegrated HoodsMicrowavesMicrowavesIntegrated MicrowavesMicrowave AccessoriesKitchen PackagesKitchen Appliance PackagesCooking AccessoriesSplashbacksWarming DrawerBuilt-in Coffee MakersMiscellaneousFridges & FreezersFridges & FreezersWhether you’re looking for a compact wine cooler or integrated American style fridge freezer, here at Electrical Discount UK we have everything you need to cater for your cooling requirements. A vital necessity to every home, fridges and freezers come in a vast range of shapes and sizes to suit every available space in your home.Fridge FreezersFridge FreezersIntegrated Fridge FreezersAmerican Fridge FreezersAmerican StyleMulti-DoorFridgesUpright FridgesIntegrated FridgesWine/Drinks CoolersFreezersUpright FreezersIntegrated FreezersChest FreezersTable Top FreezersAudio Cameras & ComputersAudio Cameras & ComputersChoose from a vast range of the latest innovative technology in our range of Hi-Fi, Audio and Cameras. We provide everything you need to create the most enjoyable and engaging entertainment system, right in the comfort of your own home.Digital CamerasCompact Digital CamerasDigital SLR CamerasBridge CamerasMemory CardsCamera AccessoriesCamcorders4K and HD CamcordersHi-FiHi-Fi SystemsMulti-Room AudioWireless SpeakersRadiosDAB RadiosAnalogue RadiosInternet RadiosClock RadiosAudio AccessoriesHeadphonesWired HeadphonesWireless HeadphonesWearable AudioAudio SeparatesTurntablesCartridgesSpeakersAmplifiersCD PlayersAV ReceiversHousehold & CleaningHousehold & CleaningWhether we like it or not, cleaning is an essential chore when it comes to maintaining our home. We aim to make your life that little bit easier by providing safe and effective cleaning products for carrying out even the dirtiest of duties.
Floor CareUpright VacuumsCylinder VacuumsCordless VacuumsSteam Cleaners & MopsHandheld VacuumsCarpet CleanersRobotic CleanersFloor PolishersVacuum AccessoriesSmall Kitchen AppliancesKettlesToastersBread MakersFood PreparationKitchen Aids & EssentialsSandwich ToastersSmall Cooking AppliancesCoffee MachinesPod Coffee MachinesEspresso MachinesBean to Cup MachinesNespresso MachinesFilter Coffee MachinesHeating & CoolingFiresFire SuitesHeatersAir PurifiersAir ConditionersDehumidifiersRadiatorsElectric BlanketsPhonesHome PhonesHome SecuritySmart HomeVideo DoorbellTechnologySegwayElectric BikesShop By BrandsCHRISTMAS SAVINGS
Account
Privacy Policy
Home
Privacy Policy
General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)Effective Date: 25th May 2018
Electrical Discount UK Privacy Policy.
This Privacy Policy describes the data protection practices of Electrical Discount UK (“ we, us or our”).Electrical Discount UK provides services in Mainland UK (England, Wales and Scotland).
PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY TO UNDERSTAND HOW WE HANDLE YOUR INFORMATION. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE INFORM US AS SOON AS POSSIBLE. IF YOU HAVE USED OUR SERVICES SUBJECT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY PLEASE CONTACT US IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THE BELOW.
This Privacy policy contains the following sections
The information we collect
How we use your information
How we share and disclose your information
Retention of your information
Right to stop or limit our processing of your data
How can you stop the use of your personal data for direct marketing
Data subject rights and your choices
Third party links and features
How we protect your information
The information we collect
Name
Address including post code
Phone numbers both land line and mobile
Email addresses
Date of birth
Items sold including Manufacturer, model, serial number and date bought
How we use your information
For delivery / collection of equipment
Emailing of offers from us
We offer extended warranties
Third party warranty providers
We provide your details to a manufacturer if an in-warranty repair is required
If there is a manufacturer promotion we provide details to that manufacturer
We may provide your details if a manufacturer requires this for a safety recall
We provide your details to Trade Debt Recovery, if an item or items are not paid for, in order to recover the debt
Notification to the Police in case of fraud
How we share and disclose your information
Paperwork for delivery / collection one copy left with customer, one returned and kept for our records
Phone / voice and / or electronically for repairs
Emailing of details for extended warranties
Manufacturer safety recall if requested, Email in spread sheet form
Manufacturer promotions and / or warranty registration / repair this will be provided electronically
Trade Debt Recovery for debt collection, details provided electronically
Police in case of fraud electronically
Retention of your information
The length of time we keep your information depends on the purposes for which it was collected and use it and / or as required to comply with applicable laws.
Right to stop or limit our processing of your data
You have the right to object to us processing your personal information if you do not think we are entitled to use it any more. You can also have your information deleted if we are keeping it too long or have its processing restricted in certain circumstances.
Where we rely on our legitimate interests, as set out under 'How we use your personal information', You may object to us using information for the purposes set out under 'How we use your information' section above. If we agree that your objection is justified in accordance with your rights under data protection laws, we’ll permanently stop using your data for those purposes. Otherwise we’ll provide you with our justification as to why we need to continue using your data.
You may also ask us to restrict the use of your personal information if:
It is not accurate.
It has been used unlawfully but you don't want us to delete it.
It's not relevant any more, but you want us to keep it for use in legal claims.
You’ve already asked us to stop using your data but you’re waiting for us to tell you if we’re allowed to keep on using it.
Please note that we may be required by law to retain certain information. Before we are able to provide you with any information or correct any inaccuracies, we may ask you provide other details to help us respond to your request.
If you would like to exercise these rights, please contact us .
How can you stop the use of your personal data for direct marketing (Newsletters, Social Media Messages etc)
We will NOT send you Newsletters or any Social Media messages if you tell us not to.
You can click the "unsubscribe" link in any NEWSLETTER that we send to you which will automatically unsubscribe you from that type of communication. Please note that you may continue to receive Service communications in relation to the product and services we have sold to you (i.e warranties etc)
Alternatively, you can unsubscribe by submitting your request here  .
Please note that it may take up to 28 days to process your request.
Data subject rights and your choices
You have certain rights with respect to your information as further described in this section.
Your Legal Rights
If you would like further information in relation to your legal rights under applicable law or would like to exercise any of them, please contact us via email customerservice@electricaldiscountuk.co.uk
Provide access to and / or a copy of information we hold about you.
The right to be informed.
The right of rectification if any details are incorrect.
The right of erasure ie. Be forgotten and have your Name, address, email and date of birth removed.
The right to restrict processing ie. We can hold your details but not use for marketing or warranties.
The right to data portability, this only applies to personal data and would usually be provided in word or excel format.
The right to object and the right not to be subject to automated decision making.
Third party links and features
We provide details to where applicable
Domestic and General (extended warranty providers).
Retra Care (extended warranty providers).
Solocare (extended warranty providers).
Furdeco (delivery service).
Online Express (delivery service).
Parcel Force (delivery service).
Paypal
Amazon
Ebay
21 Digital (web site developers)
Reference Point (secure EPOS retail computer system)
Hitachi Finance (credit or buy now pay later)
Secure Trading (to process payments)
Trade Debt Recovery (for non payment of accounts)
We also, where appropriate, provide details to:
A manufacturer for a safety recall or under warranty repair.
Experian if we need to do a credit check.
How we protect your information
All data is keep on a closed server at Reference Point which is closed to the world and only opened to specific IP addresses, all data is run over https, so it is encrypted.
Data breaches
Reference Point continually monitor the system for data breaches and have a system in place to notify affected users.
Our data Protection Officer
Calvin Casper
If you have any questions/comments about privacy, you should contact us or write to:
Mr C Casper, Electrical Discount UK, 81 Northgate, BLACKBURN, Lancashire BB2 1AA
Legal
Newsletters
Privacy Policy
Terms & Conditions
